(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T01:46:44.333702",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ピンポンパンポーン
Ding-dong-ding-dong
どうやら運営さんが半泣きになりながらね、機材を頑張っていじってくれたおかげで
Apparently, thanks to the management working hard on the equipment while practically in tears,
直りました！
it's fixed!
待ってくださった皆さんありがとうございます！
Thank you to everyone who waited!
えー、先ほど見れなかったために、えっと、見れなかった方の為にさっきと同じね、あの映像を流します。
Um, for those who couldn't watch earlier, for those who missed it, we're going to replay the same footage as before.
これから、え、ちゃんとお誕生日3D配信開始いたしますのでしっかりみんな目に焼き付けてくれよな！
From now on, um, we'll properly start the birthday 3D stream, so everyone make sure to burn it into your eyes!
では、GOー！
Now then, let's go!
始まっているじゃないか。
It's already started.
はーい、皆さんこんばんは！
Hi everyone, good evening!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです。
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers.
今日は僕のお誕生日会に遊びに来てくれてどうもありがとー！
Thank you so much for coming to play at my birthday party today!
今日はですね、僕のホロライブに入ってから2回目の誕生日ということで
Today is my second birthday since joining Hololive,
なんかこう去年とは違うことがしたいなあって思ったので今回はね、今までやったことがない歌ライブに挑戦してみようかなと思います！
and since I thought I wanted to do something different from last year, this time I thought I'd try taking on a singing live performance like I've never done before!
しかもね、僕1人で配信するときにこのアイドル衣装を使うのは初めてなんじゃないかな？
And you know, I think this might be my very first time wearing this idol outfit when streaming by myself?
いやー、すごい僕もね、楽しみにしてたし、この日のためにたくさん練習してきたとことことことことこと、ことと、あの準備してきたこととかたくさんあるのでみんなに楽しんでいってもらえればなと、思います。
Man, I was really looking forward to it, and I've practiced a ton for this day, and prepared all sorts of things, so I hope you all enjoy it.
あとこのね、こっちか。このリボンがね、よく見ると、なんかおにぎりの体みたいになってるのがちょっとジワるなって、ちょっと着替えてね、身につけてから思いました。
Also, this, oh, this side. This ribbon, if you look closely, looks a bit like an onigiri's body, which made me chuckle a bit after changing and putting it on.
え、あとね、この今日のはっしゅたぐのお知らせです。ハッシュタグ #おかゆの生誕祭2021 でつぶやいてくれると、僕が配信終わったあとにね、Twitterでペペペペってみてる時に探しやすいので、ぜひハッシュタグ #おかゆの生誕祭2021 でつぶやいてください。
Um, also, here's an announcement about today's hashtag. If you tweet with the hashtag #OkayuBirthday2021, it'll be easy for me to find when I'm checking Twitter with 'pe-pe-pe-pe' after the stream, so please tweet with the hashtag #OkayuBirthday2021.
「の」だからね！大事なのは「の」だからね！「の」がないと違うタグになっちゃうからね！みんななら「の」ちゃんと入れられるって信じてるからね！
It has 'no'! The important part is 'no'! If there's no 'no', it becomes a different tag! I believe you guys can all include 'no' properly!
はい、ということで、え、あ、運営さんからね、なんかケーキが届いてるとかなんか言ってたんだけど、ケーキないよね？
Yes, so, um, oh, the management said something about a cake arriving, but there's no cake, right?
ん？
Hm?
あ！はあーー、出てきたーー！ケーキだーー！
Ah! Whoa, it appeared! It's a cake!
え、これ全部、お、う、わ、あ、フライング、フライングで、フライング
Wait, all of this—whoa, flying, flying, flying—
フライング！
Flying!
ちょっとフライングでケーキ取っちゃったんですけど
So, I got the cake flying, but...
これね、あの、僕に用意してくれたケーキらしくて
this is supposed to be the cake prepared for me,
本来ならね、こうやって、プすって刺すとこから始めたかったんですけど
and normally, I wanted to stab it in like... "Boop!"
僕のこの手際のねばるさで、手癖の悪さで、ケーキをもうキャッチしてしまいました。
because of my clumsy, awkward hands, I ended up catching the cake!
でもこのケーキ、早速ね、いただいちゃおうかなと思います。やっぱ美味しそうなのでね。
But I think I'll go ahead and have a slice of this cake since it looks delicious.
じゃあ、いただきまーす！
So, let's dig in!
んむんむんむんむ、美味しい！美味しい！
Yum, yum, yum, yum! Delicious! Delicious!
ねえ、みんなも食べたいの？
Do you guys want some too?
どうしようかな？
What should I do?
食べたいですか？
Do you want to eat some?
お？聞こえない、よく聞こえない。え？
Huh? I can't hear you. I really can't hear you. Huh?
待って待って待って待って。食べたいですか？
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Do you want to eat some?
しょうがないな。
Oh well.
じゃあ、特別にね、おにぎり、カモン！
So, I've prepared a special onigiri... Come on!
きたー！これがね、みんなに食べさせようと思ってたケーキです。
Here it is! This is the cake I wanted everyone to eat.
どらー！喰えー！
Take that! Eat up!
うんうんうんうんうん、あ、美味しいね！美味しかった！
Mhm, mhm, mhm, mhm. Ah, it's delicious! It was delicious!
よかった！
I'm glad!
この底のね、底についてる生クリームと海苔のハーモニーが絶妙なんじゃないですか？絶妙ですやんね。
Isn't the harmony of the raw cream and nori at the bottom exquisite? It's exquisite, right?
よし、みんなが「おにぎりケーキ」を食べたということで、僕はそろそろ歌のライブの準備に向かいたいと思います！
Alright, now that everyone has eaten the onigiri cake, I should get ready for my singing live!
じゃあみんな、後に続けー！
Alright everyone, let's keep going!
キラキラ光る流星群
Glittering, shining shooting star cluster,
わたし想うわウォーリーニー
I'm thinking of you, wǒ ài nǐ.
星のままに逃避行 呼呼、そんなストーリーも悪くないのさ
Even a runaway flight in the stars, hum, isn't a bad story.
ネオンの街からプレビュー
A preview from the neon streets,
月世界までウォンビーロン
Wonnibeon all the way to the moon world.
あの星の名も忘れたの
I've even forgotten that star's name,
満つ月の飛行
flying under the full moon.
彗星ハネムーン あなたとランデヴ 恋をしているのさふたり
愛してモナムール いっそふたりきり どっか遠くへいこうか
曖昧なエアライン 言葉はいらない やっと出逢えたあなたと
曖昧なエアライン 言い訳はいらない やっと出逢えたあなたと
星巡り繰り返し 目指すは宇宙の終着点さ
アハハーン アハハーン あははん アハハーン アハハーン うぉおお
Ahaha... Ahaha... Uoooo...
小天体のライナー その数回転のあいだ 運命星も越えた 愛の瞬きがプレイバック
A liner of minor celestial bodies, a playback of love's twinkle,
環状線結いだ あなたは終点ライダー
looping around the orbital line, you are the terminal rider,
ロマンス飛行を今 動かない信号の赤色
now taking a romantic flight.
月世界までウォーリーニー
Moon world until wǒ ài nǐ,
モスクワの海が旅の終わり そこでお別れさ
Moscow's sea is the end of the journey, and that's where we say goodbye.
彗星ハネムーン あなたとランデヴ 恋をしているのさふたり
愛してモナムール 由縁なんてなくても いいよ遠くへいこうか
彗星ハネムーン 果てまでランデヴ そうさ今だけはふたり
ねえ聞いてモナムール 片道切符でもいいですか？
夜が明けたら何処へいこうか 永久に出逢えぬあなたと 星巡り繰り返し
目指すは夢の出発点さ
Aiming for the starting point of dreams
アハーン アハーン あははん
Ah-ha-han, ah-ha-han, a-ha-han
アハーン アハーン うぉおお
Ah-ha-han, ah-ha-han, u-oo-oo
はあ...
Haa...
聞こえますか 皆さん？
Can you hear me, everyone?
疲れた...
I'm exhausted...
体力がないからさ
Because I don't have much stamina,
歌いながら動くとやばいマジで
singing and moving at the same time is seriously dangerous...
なんかさ、さっきTwitterでさ、僕の枠がうまくいかなかったでしょ？
You know, earlier on Twitter, my stream frame didn't go well, right?
そんときにさ、ホロライブのみんながさ、なんかおかゆの新しい枠はこっちだよみたいなふうにさ、なんか連絡してくれてるの見てさ、
And at that time, seeing everyone from Hololive reaching out and guiding the stream frame,
もうさ、ちょっと泣きそうになっちゃった
I almost started crying...
なんかもうさ、ちょっと不安になっちゃってさ
I got a bit anxious and all,
なんか今日放送できないのかなって思ったんだけどさ
thinking "Can I not broadcast today?",
それでもみんな信じて、なんか枠の誘導してくれてんの見てさ
but seeing everyone trust me and help guide the stream frame,
もうなんか... もう感無量だよ！私これから始まったばっかりなのに！
I was like... I'm so overwhelmed with emotion! Even though I've only just started!
まあ、まあいいや。えっと...
Well, oh well. Um...
あの、どうでした？水星ハネムーンは。ちょっとくるくるこうやってね、回ってみたりとかしたりしてさ。
how was it? Suisei Honeymoon. I spun around like this and stuff.
よかったかな？かわいかったかな？
Was it good? Was it cute?
ちょっとみんなにね、かわいいって思ってもらえるように動こうと思ってたから、そう思ってもらえたならね、よかった。よかったです。はあ...
I wanted to move so that everyone would think it's cute, so if you felt that way, I'm glad. I'm so glad. Haa...
やばい、なんかこのまましゃべり続けてるとさ、なんか泣きそうになっちゃうから、もう次に行こうと思います。
Oh no, if I keep talking like this, I'm gonna start crying, so I think I'll move on to the next thing.
夢ちゃんいいですか？次、音楽のミュージックの準備はOKですか？
Yume-chan, is it okay? Next, is the music preparation ready?
OKということなので、次いきたいと思います！次の曲は...こちら！
Since it's a-ok, let's go to the next! The next song is... right here!
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
Because truthfully, I'm crazy!
白鳥たちはそう 見えないとこでバタ足するんです
'Cause even swans, you know, flutter their legs where they can't be seen
本能に従順 忠実 翻弄も重々承知
True to my instincts, loyal, fully aware of being toyed with
前途洋々だし… だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
I got a bright future, after all... which is why I'll take a rest sometimes
この目でしっかり見定めて 行き先地図上マークして
With your own eyes, ascertain it carefully and mark it on your map
近道あればそれが王道 はしゃげる翼があれば上等
When there's a shortcut, you got a right to take it; even better if you got wings
ヤバ爪割れた グルーで補修した
Crap, you break a nail, then fix it with glue
それだけでなんか達成感
And just that somehow gives you a sense of achievement
大事なのは自分 かわいがること
The most important thing is to care for yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ 他人も愛せない
You gotta love yourself before you can love someone else
Please don't say "You are lazy" だって本当はcrazy
Please don't say "You are lazy" Because truthfully, I'm crazy!
能ある鷹はそう 見えないところにピック隠すんです
'Cause even the skilled hawk, you know, hides his picks where they can't be seen
想像に一生懸命 現実ば絶体絶命
Dream with all you got, 'cause reality's a desperate situation
発展途中だし… だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
I'm still growing, after all... which is why I might suddenly go off pitch
その目に映らないだけだって やりはメーター振り切って
Your will is a meter long, even if it's not in front of your eyes
いつでも全力で夢見て その分全力で眠って
Always try to dream with all your might and sleep with all your might
ヤリちょい痩せた 調子づいて喰った
Awesome, you get a bit thinner, and then eat happily
それだけでなんで? 敗北感
And just that, why? Makes you feel defeated
すかさずに出発 下方修正して
You have to lower your expectations right away
柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
Those that adapt quickly win
Flexible and adaptable, a master of disguise wins!
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
'Cause it's really crazy
孔雀たちはそう ここぞというとき美を見せるんです
Peacocks show their beauty when it counts, you see.
五臓六腑 満身 邁進 願望は痩身 麗人
Organs, whole body, rushing forward, wishing to be a slender beauty—
誘惑多発だし… だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
Temptations are everywhere... so my willpower totally shatters.
ヤバ まさかの赤点！？ いや ギリクリア！
Oh no, a failing grade?! No, barely passed!
それだけでなんて全能感
That alone gives me such a sense of omnipotence.
大事なのは自分 認めてくこと
The important thing is accepting yourself.
自分を許さなきゃ 他人も許せない
If you can't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others either.
Please don't say "You are lazy"
だって本当はcrazy
'Cause it's really crazy
白鳥たちはそう 見えないところでバタ足するんです
Swans are paddling furiously where you can't see them.
本能に忠順 忠実 翻弄も重々承知
Obedient to instinct, fully aware of being toyed with.
前途洋々だし… だからたまになんか休憩しちゃうんです
The future is bright... so sometimes I just take a break.
皆さん、水飲んでいいすか？
Everyone, do you mind if I drink some water?
水飲んでいいすか？
Can I drink some water?
うまし、うまし。喉なった。
Delicious, delicious. My throat's cleared up.
えーと、とりあえず、Don't say “lazy”どうでした？
Um, anyway, how was "Don't say 'lazy'"?
もうなんかね、この曲は、かっこいいから、もうなんか…
I mean, you know, this song is so cool, so I was like...
かっこよく歌えてたかな？
Did I sing it coolly?
もうなんかさ、心臓が、心臓がドキドキしてるよ、僕も。
Man, my heart, my heart is pounding so hard right now.
でもね、まだまだ、まだまだ、みんなには聴いてほしい歌がたくさんあるので、それも楽しみにしてて下さい。
But you know, there are still so many songs I want you all to hear, so please look forward to those too.
おっ、ここで何やらゲストの、ゲストが来てくれるらしい！
Oh, apparently some guest, a guest is going to come join us!
誰だ？
Who is it?
え、みんな誰だと思う？
Eh, who do you guys think it is?
みんなゲスト誰だと思う？
Who do you guys think the guest is?
ちょっと予想を予想。
Go ahead and guess!
えーっと、ころさん、ころさんしかいないね。
Um... Korosan, it has to be Korosan.
ころさんしかいないじゃん。
It's definitely Korosan.
いや僕のね、大事な人ですよ、僕の大事な人がね、来てくれますよ。
Well, she's an important person to me. My important person is coming.
はい。
Yes.
上映（名前）呼んでもいいですか？
Can I call her out?
よし、では僕の大事な人と言えば、言っていきましょうか。
Alright, then speaking of my important person, let's say it.
えー、シオン、あくあ、えー、スバルちゃん、
Uh, Shion, Aqua, uh, Subaru-chan...
おい！
Hey!
おっ！
Oh!
おい！
Hey!
どこ？ここだよ！
Where? Right here!
右下だよ！
Bottom right!
来たーー！！
She's here!!
ひろひろ言いたいことあるんですけど。何？何？シオン？え？何々？スバルちゃん？あくあちゃん？
Hirohiro, I have something I want to say. What? What? Shion? Eh? What is it? Subaru-chan? Aqua-chan?
一番大事な人は、最後に取っておくのが、そういうやつじゃん。
The most important person is someone you save for last, right?
おかゆ、おめでとう！
Okayu, congratulations!
ありがとう！今日何しに来てくれたの？
Thank you! What did you come here to do today?
今日は、あの、せっかくのね、おかゆがこうやってアイドル衣装を着て配信してるから、
Today, since Okayu is wearing her idol outfit and streaming,
ま、ちょっといろんなポーズをとってもらおうかなと思って。
I thought I'd have her strike various poses.
待って いろんなポーズ？
Wait, various poses?
そう。
That's right.
なになに？どんな、どんなポーズをさせようとしてるの、僕に？
What, what? What kind of pose are you trying to make me do?
え、今もうやっちゃっていいの？
Eh, can I just do it now?
いいよ。
Sure.
いい？ じゃあ、マジで這いつくばってくれる？
Alright? Then, will you seriously crawl on the ground?
え、じゃあ、あ、じゃあ、這いつくばります。這いつくばるって何、こういうこと？
Eh, well, then, I'll crawl. What does crawling mean, like this?
あ、いいよ、いいよ。そうそうそう、這いつくばって、
Ah, good, good. That's right, crawl down,
カメラマンさんに指示が、カメラ目線を。カメラ、カメラマンさんにちょっと、もうちょっと上からかな。
Give instructions to the cameraman, look at the camera. Cameraman, maybe a little bit from above.
ねぇ、ハイキンス死ぬよ？ハイキンス死ぬよ？
Hey, my back muscles will die! My back muscles will die!
あ、可愛い。おかゆ、カメラ目線できる？ハイキンこれ以上顔上げたら僕ハイキン死んじゃうけど。
Ah, cute. Okayu, can you look at the camera? If I lift my face any higher, my back muscles will die.
じゃあ、カメラマンさんがちょっと下がってもらってな。
Then, cameraman, can you back up a bit?
下に。いける？カメラマンさん。もっと下？下だよ、下、下、下、下、いいんじゃない？
Lower. Can you? Cameraman. Lower? It's lower, lower, lower, isn't that good?
で、ちょっと、ええと、左側にこう、体の、お尻もちょっと見えるぐらいにやってよ、カメラマンさん。
And, um, to the left side, so that part of your body and butt are visible too, cameraman.
動けます？
Can you move?
お。めっちゃ困っとるじゃん、カメラマンさん。
Oh, the cameraman is in a lot of trouble.
どう？もっと？僕のことか？
How's that? More? You mean me?
あ、可愛い、可愛い、可愛い。あ、いいよ、いいよ、そうそう、そっちがいい、そっちがいい、そっちがいい、そっちがいい。
Ah, cute, cute, cute. Ah, good, good, that's right, that's better, that's better, that's better.
あ、可愛い、可愛い、可愛い。にゃんにゃん。
Ah, cute, cute, cute. Nyan nyan.
にゃんにゃん。そしたらじゃあ、少し体を起こしてもらって、
Nyan nyan. Then, raise your body up a little bit,
ほい。
Hoi.
起こせる？起こした？いいよ。あ、起こした。
Can you raise it? Did you raise it? Good. Ah, you raised it.
ええと、あごに、え、両手でグーパンチ。
Um, to the chin, uh, a double-fist punch with both hands.
あ、そうそうそう。そうそうそう。え、ちょっとそう。それで、ちょっとなんか照れてる感じを
Ah, that's right. That's right. Uh, a bit like that. Then, kind of a shy feeling,
やってほしいな。
I want you to do that.
照れてないもん。
I'm not shy at all.
照れてるでしょ？
You are shy, right?
照れてないもん。
I'm not shy!
照れてるでしょ？
You are shy, right?
照れてないもん。
I'm not shy!
あ、可愛い、可愛い。早い可愛い。
Ah, cute, cute. So cute.
やだな。
No way.
じゃあ、そしたら後ろ向いて、
Then, turn around backwards,
振り返ってほしいな、うん。
I want you to look back, yeah.
って振り返るの？
You want me to turn back like that?
振り返れる？文字文字しなが…文字文字しながら…え、立ったほうがいいんじゃね、でも、そしたら。
Can you turn back? Fidgeting... fidgeting... Eh, wouldn't it be better to stand up, though?
あ、じゃあ、立って、立って。で、尻尾も映してほしいな、カメラマンさん。尻尾も。尻尾も映してほしい。
Ah, then stand up, stand up. And, I want you to capture the tail too, cameraman. The tail too. I want you to capture the tail.
映ってる？内緒。あ、内緒じゃなくて、ねえ。
Is it captured? Secret. Ah, not secret, hey.
そしたらね、ちょっと、もっと、映ってほしいな。え、何？ちらって後ろを振り返って映ってほしいな。
Then, um, I want it to be captured a bit more. Eh, what? I want you to glance back and show it.
こっちも受ける？ちらり。
Do you accept this side too? Glance.
ああ、可愛いねえ。
Ah, so cute.
上手にできてると？
Am I doing it well?
うん、とっても上手だよ。可愛いね。こうさん大好き。
Yeah, you're doing very well. So cute. I love Okayu.
え、死んだ、一瞬死んだんですけど。死んだの？死んだ。おかゆ、おにぎりゃーのこと大好きって見せつけてるんだこれは。ねえ、おにぎりゃーのみんなも大好き。
Eh, I died, I died for a second. You died? I died. Okayu is showing how much she loves Onigirya. Hey, I love all the Onigirya too.
そうだね、それはもう
That's true, that's already
それはもう仕方なし。そうだの。それは仕方なしだね。
that can't be helped. Is that so. That can't be helped, right?
仕方なし。ええと、どうしよう。
Can't be helped. Um, what should we do?
あ、あとどうしようかな。もう限界かしすぎて音声やばいじゃん。
Ah, what should I do next? You're being too cute, the audio is getting crazy.
ガビガビガビガビガビガビ…やばい。
Glitchy glitchy glitchy... Oh no.
もうなんかね、テンションが上がるに伴ってね、回線も不安定になってきてる。
As my tension goes up, the connection is starting to get unstable.
やばい、やばい。もっと一緒にいたいのに。
Oh no, oh no. Even though I want to be together more.
あの、ちょっと一緒に、待って、これからずっと一緒にいようと思ってるんだけどさ、無理なのかな？
Um, let's stay together, wait, I was planning to be together forever from now on, is that impossible?
でもなんか回線がね、ダメって言ってるよ。
But the connection is saying no.
ほら、もうね、連れてかれ始めてる。
Look, I'm already starting to get dragged away.
やだなの？
You don't want that?
回線が…いや、回線やだ、機材トラブルやめてよ。ころさんのほうまで。
The connection... No, connection, stop with the equipment trouble. Even up to Korone's end.
じゃあ、じゃあなんかすごいカカカカカってなっちゃってるから、
So, since it's making all these glitchy sounds,
どうする？シンプルな指示もらおうか、じゃあ。
What should we do? Shall we get some simple instructions, then?
シンプルな指示。会話しようとするとガババババってなるから、
Simple instructions. Because whenever we try to talk it goes all glitched out,
こうして、こうして、みたいな。
like 'do this, do that'.
あ、にゃあにゃあ。にゃあにゃあ。にゃあにゃあ。にゃあにゃあ。にゃあにゃあ。にゃあにゃあ。にゃあにゃあ。
Ah, nyan nyan. Nyan nyan. Nyan nyan. Nyan nyan. Nyan nyan. Nyan nyan. Nyan nyan.
あ、聞こえてる？これ、聞こえてないのかな。可愛いよ。
Ah, can you hear me? Can you not hear this? So cute.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
どんどん世界のが…あ、聞こえてる、聞こえてる。世界のバランスが崩れ始めてる。
The world's... Ah, I can hear you. The balance of the world is starting to collapse.
聞こえてる。聞こえてる。もう連れてかれそう、やばい。
I can hear you. I can hear you. I'm about to be dragged away, oh no.
おいおいおい 連れて行かれそう
Hey, hey, hey, looks like she's getting dragged away.
そうだね またね
That's right, see ya.
じゃあね じゃあね
Bye-bye, bye-bye.
またね またね またね
See ya, see ya, see ya.
まって まって まって
Wait, wait, wait.
ああ 何？
Ah, what?
行ってしまった
She's gone.
連れて行かれた、というほうが正しいんだろうか
Well, "dragged away" is probably more accurate.
本人はね、すごく嫌がってたんですけどね
I mean, she really didn't want to go, though.
あ、連れて行かれちゃいましたね
Ah, she got dragged away.
え、じゃあコメントから何か1つくらいやって次の歌に行こうかな
Um, well, let's do one thing from chat before moving to the next song.
みんな、みんなどうどうどうどう何してほしい？何してほしい？
Everyone, what do you want me to do? What do you want?
どういうのがいい？にゃんにゃんポーズもやったし、振り向きもやったし
What kind of pose? I did the cat pose, and the look-back pose...
どうかな、どうかな
I wonder what's next...
チュウ、チュウは無理だよ、チュウは。あ、投げキッスてなったこと
A kiss? No way, a kiss is... Oh, a flying kiss!
じゃあ、やるか。じゃあ、カメラマンさんのカメラに向かってね、投げキッスするので受け取ってください
Alright, I'll do it. I'll blow a kiss at the cameraman's camera, so please catch it.
じゃあ
Here goes.
いいですか？いきますよ
Ready? Here I go.
おにぎりゃーの皆さん、いつも応援ありがとう
Onigirya, thank you always for your support!
はい、次行くぞ！
Alright, time for the next one!
次行くぞ、次行くぞ、次行くぞ、次行くぞ、次行くぞ！
Next one, next one, next one, next one, next one!
では、次の曲こちら！
Now, for the next song... right here!
江戸の街は今日も深く 夜の帳かけていく
The streets of Edo are deep today,
and the deep curtain of night falls down again
鏡向いて 紅を引いて 応じるまま受け入れるまま
Facing the mirror, putting on lipstick,
complying and accepting it all
橙輝いた花 憧れてた望んでいた
The orange flower which shone,
I had admired and desired
いつの間にか 藍色の花 けれいど私安くないわ
Before I knew it, I was a blue flower,
but I'm not that cheap
まことは ただ一人のどなたかの為だけに咲いていたのだけれど
In truth, I only wanted to bloom
for one special someone...
運命はわっちの自由を奪い そいで歯車を回していくのでありんす
...but fate stole my freedom
and kept spinning its gears.
偽りだらけの恋愛 そして私を抱くのね
A love full of lies,
and then you embrace me
悲しいくらいに感じた振りの吉原 今日は雨
Acting almost as if it could feel grief,
Yoshiwara, it's raining today
貴方様どうか私を 買って戴けないでしょうか
Sir, would you somehow
buy me please?
咲き出す 傘の群れに 濡れる私は雨
In the crowd of umbrellas
starting to bloom, drenched, I'm raining
行き交う群れ 賑わう声が ひしめき合いもつれ合い
The bustling voices of the passing crowd,
jostling and tangling
願うことは どうかいつか 鳥かごの外連れ出して
My wish is to somehow, someday,
get brought out of this birdcage
まことは 行く宛などなくなってしまったのだけれど
In truth, I had no place
to go anymore,
あなたの方の中から見える景色だけは わっちをいかなる時も 癒してくれるのでありんす
but the scenery seen from inside this cage
will always heal me at any time.
偽りだらけの恋愛 そして私を買うのね
A love full of lies,
and then you buy me
私に咲いた花びら 濡れる心に降る雨
Petals that bloomed on me,
the rain falling on my drenched heart
貴方様どうか 私と一夜限りの戯れを
Sir, please have
a night of play with me
望む シミの数が 鈍く心に刺さる
The dull number of stains
pierce my heart
憂いを帯びた花 望む 果てる
A flower tinged with sorrow,
wishing for an end
ようこそおいでくんまし
Welcome, please come in
恋人ごっこの夜に 吐息「あっァ」と鳴かせて
In this night of lovers' play,
making me moan "Ah-ah"
悲しいくらいに感じた振りの吉原 今日は雨
Acting almost as if it could feel grief,
Yoshiwara, it's raining today
偽りだらけの恋愛 そして私を抱くのね
A love full of lies,
and then you embrace me
悲しいくらいに感じた 振りの吉原 今日は雨
Acting almost as if it could feel grief,
Yoshiwara, it's raining today
貴方様どうか私を 買って戴けないでしょうか
Sir, would you somehow
buy me please?
咲き出す 傘の群れに 濡れる私は雨
In the crowd of umbrellas
starting to bloom, drenched, I'm raining
咲き出す傘の群れに 濡れる私は雨
In the crowd of umbrellas opening up, I am the rain getting wet.
はい。吉原ラメントだったんだけど、どう...
Yep, that was Yoshiwara Lament, but how...
どうだったかな？
How was it?
この歌はよく、あの、歌枠とかでやってる時に歌ったら、
When I sing this song during my singing streams,
みんなすごいこの歌好きって言ってくれてたし、何よりなんか僕のね、ばあちゃんがこの歌をめちゃめちゃ気に入ってて
everyone always says how much they love it. And above all, my grandma loves this song so, so much!
おかゆの吉原ラメント好きなんだよねって言ってたから、
She always tells me, "I love Okayu's Yoshiwara Lament."
あの今日は僕の誕生日ということで、いつもお世話になってる、
So since today is my birthday, to thank her for always taking care of me—
まあ今はね、そばには、おうちには住んでないんだけれども、ばあちゃんがそう言ってくれたので、今回はこの歌を選ばせていただきました。
Well, she doesn't live right next door or in the same house anymore, but since she said that, I chose this song for today.
どうだった？みんなセクシーじゃなかった、僕？
How was it? Wasn't I sexy, everyone?
みんなにさ、投げキッスした後に、なんか歌うとちょっとさ、さっきの投げキッスすらも偽りだったんじゃないかみたいな感じになっちゃうんだけど
After blowing everyone a kiss, if I sing right after, it almost feels like even that kiss was a lie or something.
ばあちゃん見てる！？ばあちゃん見てる！？ばあちゃん！僕アイドルになっちゃったよ！
Grandma, are you watching?! Grandma, are you watching?! Grandma! I've become an idol!
ばあちゃんにはね、ホロライブに入る時には、なんかゲーマーズっていうのがあって、そこでおう、入れるらしいから行ってくるねって言ったんだけど、
When I joined Hololive, I told my grandma, "There's this group called Gamers, and it sounds like I can join, so I'm gonna go do that."
ばあちゃんもまさか僕がね、この僕がアイドルになるだなんて思ってなかっただろうね、正直。
She probably never expected that I—that *I* would become an idol, honestly.
みんなコメントありがとね！歌ってる時もね、みんなのコメントを見ながら二者三脚してました。
Thanks for all the comments, everyone! Even while singing, I was keeping pace with everyone's comments.
え、トレンド1位？本当に！？
Eh, trending #1? Really?!
ありがとうこれ！これみんながおかゆの、おかゆの生誕祭2021をつぶやいてくれてるおかげだね。
Thank you so much! This is all thanks to everyone tweeting about Okayu's Birthday Celebration 2021.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ、次もね、あの、頑張って歌っていこうと思います。
Well then, I'm going to do my best singing the next song too!
では、次の曲、どうぞー！
Now then, here is the next song!
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good,
もう そんなんじゃほら
look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
言葉にすれば 消えちゃう関係なら
If words will ruin our relationship,
言葉を消えばいいやって 思ってた 恐れてた
then we won't need them, or so I thought, so I feared.
だけど あれ？ なんかちがうかも…
But wait. Something might be different...
千里の道も一歩から
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step.
石のようにかたい そんな意志で ちりもつもればやまとだでしこ？
With a resolution as firm as stone, will dust pile up into a traditional beauty?
「し」ぬきで いや死ぬ気で！
Doing my best without the "shi", no, with all my life!
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy, just you calling my name makes me float to the sky.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering, just you smiling makes me smile.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも めぐり逢えたことがしあわせなの
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate, meeting you is my happiness.
でも そんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good,
もう そんなんじゃほら
look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
そう そんなんじゃいやだ
Yup, I don't want it like that.
ねぇ そんなんじゃまだ 私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Hey, that's not enough yet. Please keep looking at me, forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど あなたの中の私の存在は まだまだ大きくないことも わかっているけれど
Even though I know my presence inside you isn't as big as your presence inside me yet,
今この同じ 瞬間 共有してる 実感
the reality that we share this exact moment right now—
ちりもつもればやまとだでしこ？ 略して？ちりもつやまとなでしこ！
Will dust pile up into a traditional beauty? Shortened? Dust pile traditional beauty!
くらくらり くらくらる あなたを見上げたら それだけでまぶしすぎて
Dizzy and spinning, spinning and dizzy, looking up at you is just too dazzling.
くらくらる くらくらり あなたを想っている それだけでとけてしまう
Spinning and dizzy, dizzy and spinning, just thinking about you makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも めぐり逢えたことがしあわせなの
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate, meeting you is my happiness.
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
The fact that we were able to meet is such happiness.
コイスル キセツハ ヨクパリ circulation
The season of love is a greedy circulation.
コイスル キモチハ ヨクパリ circulation
The feeling of love is a greedy circulation.
コイスル ヒトミハ ヨクパリ circulation
The eyes in love are a greedy circulation.
コイスル オトメハ ヨクパリ circulation
The maiden in love is a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Fluffy and light, just you calling my name makes me float into the sky.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Fluffy and light, just you smiling makes me smile too.
神様 ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Dear God, thank you, even if it's just a twist of fate.
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
The fact that we were able to meet is such happiness.
でも そんなんじゃだめ もう そんなんじゃ ほら 心は進化するよ もっと もっと
Even so, that's no good, hey, even so, look, my heart is evolving more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ やだ ねぇ そんなんじゃ まだ 私のこと 見ててね ずっと ずっと
Yeah, that's no good, no way, hey, that's still not enough, keep looking at me forever and ever!
はーーあ... てれるーー！
Hah... So embarrassing!
いや、この歌はさ、もうすっごい可愛いから、あの、僕声かっこいいじゃん？
I mean, this song is super cute, and my voice is cool, right?
最近の口癖なんだけど、このかっこいい僕がこれを歌ってもいいのかなあって思ってたんですけど、歌っちゃいましたね！
It's been my catchphrase lately, but I wondered if a cool guy like me could sing this, but I went ahead and sang it!
歌っちゃいました！
I sang it!
あ、でもね、みんなが可愛いって言ってくれてるなら、いいのかなあ？ いいのかなあ？いっか！
Ah, but you know, if everyone's saying it's cute, is it okay? Is it okay? Oh well!
ありがとうみんな！見えてるよコメント。見えてるよ、ありがとー！
Thank you everyone! I can see the comments. I can see them, thank you!
えーっと、右、左、上...
Um, right, left, up...
お、応援団みたいになっちゃったけど。
Oh, it turned into like a cheering squad.
右！左！上！下！聞こえるかーい？
Right! Left! Up! Down! Can you hear me?
聞こえてる。
I can hear you.
ありがとう、ありがとう！ありがとうだよー！
Thank you, thank you! Thank you so much!
ちょっと深呼吸しようか。
Let's take a deep breath.
よし、息もととのったことだし、次の歌に行こうと思うんです...
Alright, my breathing's settled, so I think I'll move on to the next song...
けど、次の歌は、いつもね、僕が燃えている、あの曲を、今日は燃えないけれども歌っていこうかなと、思います。
However, for the next song, I always get fired up, but today I won't get fired up, but I'll sing it anyway, I think.
音楽準備はいい？
Is the music ready?
では、聞いてください。ホームラ...「炎」
Now then, please listen. "Homura"
さよなら ありがとう 声の限り
"Goodbye" and "thank you," I say with all my voice.
悲しみよりもっと大事なこと
Something more important than sadness.
去りゆく背中に伝えたくて
I wanted to tell your departing back.
ぬくもりと痛みに間に合うように
So that I can make it in time for the warmth and pain.
このまま続くと思っていた 僕らの明日を描いていた
I thought it would go on just like this, picturing our tomorrows.
呼び合っていた光がまだ 胸の奥に熱いのに 僕たちは
Even though the light we called out to is still warm in the depths of our hearts, we...
僕たちは燃え盛る旅の途中で出会い
We met in the middle of a blazing journey
手を取りそして離した 未来のために
and took each other's hands before letting go, for the future.
夢が一つ叶うたび 僕は君を想うだろう
Whenever a dream comes true, I'll probably think of you.
強くなりたいと願い 泣いた 決意を胸に
With the wish to grow stronger and a tearful resolution in my chest,
懐かしい思い出に囚われたり 残酷な世界に泣き叫んで
Trapped by nostalgic memories, crying out in a cruel world,
大人になるほど増えて行く もう何一つだって失いたくない
The more I grow up, the more things pile up; I don't want to lose a single thing.
悲しみに飲まれ落ちてしまえば 痛みを感じなくなるけれど
If I were to sink and be swallowed by sadness, I'd stop feeling the pain, but...
君の言葉 君の願い 僕は守りぬくと誓ったんだ
Your words, your wish—I swore I'd protect them to the end.
音を立てて崩れ落ちて行く
It crumbles away with a sound,
一つだけの かけがえのない世界
in this one and only, irreplaceable world.
手を伸ばし抱き止めた 激しい光の束
I reached out and embraced the intense bundle of light
輝いて消えてった 未来のために
that shone and faded away for the future.
許された幸せと 約束を超えて行く
Going beyond the granted happiness and promises,
振り返らずに進むから 前だけ向いて叫ぶから
I will move forward without looking back, I will shout facing only ahead,
心に炎を灯して 遠い未来まで……
lighting a flame in my heart, until a distant future...
はいっということでついにこんなね、お歌いでホームランを歌う夢が叶いました。ありがとうございます。
Yes! So finally, my dream of singing a "home run" song like this came true. Thank you so much!
いやホームランはいいよね。私の胸もいつも燃えていますよ。はい。
Man, "home runs" are great, aren't they? My chest is always burning too, yep.
あ、でもね、ちょっと察しのいいみんなはさ、いつも私が配信して終わる時にホームラン歌ってるから、あ、これでおしまいなんだなって
Oh, but you know, for those of you quick on the uptake, since I always sing Homura when ending my streams, you probably thought, "Ah, so this is the end," right?
思いました?
Did you?
実はち、ち、ち、ち、今日はひと味違うんだなー。
Actually, t-t-t-today is a bit different.
と、いうことで、ホームランの次にもう一個あるんですけど、その前にその前にその前に、その前にめちゃめちゃね、素晴らしいお知らせがございまーす！
So, after the "home run", there's actually one more thing, but before that—before that, before that—there is a super, super wonderful announcement!
準備はいいですかー?
Are you guys ready?
はーい！
Yes!
では、行きますよ。グッズの告知でストーン！
Well then, here we go. Merch announcement, boom!
等身大タペストリーと、トウミ先生描き下ろし「おかゆも日なたぼっこで増えるさマグカップ」、
A life-sized tapestry and Tooumi-sensei's illustrated 'Okayu Sunbathing Mug Cup',
そしてこちら2点全部セットをご購入してくださった方には、特典として、
And for those who purchase the complete 2-item set,
猫又おかゆからの複製手書きラブレターが届きます！
a duplicated handwritten love letter from Nekomata Okayu will arrive!
なんとラブレターも届いちゃうんだよね。
You'll even get a love letter delivered, you know.
で、じゃあまず1つ1つ説明していきたいと思います。あ、こっちですね。
Now, let's explain them one by one. Ah, it's this one.
神岡るる先生が描き下ろししてくださった、え、僕の等身大タペストリーです。
First up is the life-sized tapestry of me illustrated by Kamioka Ruru-sensei.
僕はアホ毛込みで152cmなんだけど、お家に飾ったら僕がね、お家にいるかのようなサイズ感で、お邪魔します。
I'm 152 cm including my ahoge, but if you display it at home, it gives the size feel as if I'm actually there at your place, 'Pardon the intrusion.'
え、神岡るる先生というのは、僕の、ママです！僕のね、イラストを担当してくださっているママが今回描き下ろししてくれました！
Um, Kamioka Ruru-sensei is... my mama! The mama who handles my illustrations drew this specially for us this time!
めっちゃでかい！見て！180cmあんのよ、高く。
It's super huge! Look! It's about 180 cm tall.
あ、アホ毛抜きだったっけか。ちょっとあとで測りましょう、身長。
Ah, was that excluding the ahoge? Let's measure the height later.
70cm×160cmだって！こ、こんなんでおまじで！
It's 70cm by 160cm! Seriously, like this?!
ぜひね、ぜひ僕を、僕をお家にいれてください。
Please, please let me... let me into your home.
ちょっと伝え方によってはちょっと不審なんですけど、あの僕をお家に入れてください。はい。
Depending on how I say it, it sounds a bit suspicious, but um, please let me into your house. Yes.
次です。次の説明にいきたいと思います。
Next up. I'd like to move on to the next explanation.
こちら！えっとトウミ先生描き下ろし「おかゆも日なたぼっこで増えるさマグカップ」、こちらはですね、あのトウミ先生という方がですね、マグカップのイラストを描いてくださいました。
Here! Um, Tooumi-sensei's illustrated 'Okayu Sunbathing Mug Cup'. This one, um, a person named Tooumi-sensei drew the illustrations for the mug cup.
で、このマグカップの手の部分、持ち手の部分が猫の、この僕の、僕のね、この尻尾みたいな点灯で、ほらほら！凄いんでしょ、ほらほら！こんな感じでね、この尻尾の取っ手となっております。
And the hand part of this mug, the handle part, is like a cat's, this tail of mine, see, look! Isn't it amazing, look look! Like this, it becomes a handle shaped like a tail.
でも、あんまり強く掴みすぎるなよ。
But don't grip it too tightly, okay?
これね、僕ゲーマーズなんで、ゲームセンター仕様のこうデザインになってます。めっちゅめっちゃ可愛いよね！
Since I'm in Gamers, this is designed like an arcade machine style. It's super super cute, right?
私も、私も欲しい！私の家にも郵送してください。
I want one too! Please mail one to my house as well.
えっと、20、あれ、何時からブース公開ですか？スタッフ、うー。
Um, 20... wait, what time is the Booth opening? Staff, oo—
はい、え、概要欄にね、あのブースのURLがあるので、もう飛んだら買えるのかな？
Yes, um, there's the Booth URL in the description box, so can you buy it once you jump there?
10時25分ですか？
Is it 10:25?
はい、え、今連絡があったんですけど、販売は10時25分から、え、ブースで買えるようになるみたいなので、皆さんよかったらね、あの、買って見てください。よろしくお願いします。めちゃめちゃ可愛いと思います。
Yes, um, I just got word, sales will start at 10:25 AM, um, on Booth so you can buy them, so everyone, if you'd like, um, please go buy and check it out. Thank you very much. I think it's super cute.
えっと、え、じゃあやりますか？ぎこちないな。
Um, um, shall we do it? That was awkward.
じゃあ、皆さん、これで終わりではございません。私は、私はこの何ヶ月間も、言いたくて、言いたくて、言いたくて、言いたくてね、仕がなかったことがね、あるんです、実はね。じつじつじつは。
Well then, everyone, this isn't the end. I... I have something that for these past few months, I've just wanted so, so, so, so badly to tell you... actually, yes, truly, truly, truly.
最近、ホロライブの みんな、オリジナルの曲出してるよね。
Lately, everyone in Hololive has been releasing original songs, right?
あれ、いいなって思ってさ、僕も、いいなって、作っちゃいました！やったー！
I thought that was so nice, and so I... I went and made one too! Yay!
わいわいわいわい！
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
ということで、えー、本日はですね、その歌を歌っちゃいたいと思います！
With that said, um, today, I'd like to go ahead and sing that song!
あの、私のね、チャンネルにハテナハテナハテナっていう動画が今上がってるんですけど、そちらの方でPVだったりがこうしっかり見れるバージョンの動画があるので、22時半にプレミア公開されるのでよかったら一緒にみましょう、皆さん！ということで歌って行きたいと思います。
Um, there's a video titled '???' currently uploaded on my channel, and there's a version there where you can properly watch the PV and everything, and it premieres at 10:30 PM, so if you'd like, let's watch it together, everyone! With that said, I'd like to go ahead and sing it.
思います。
I think.
よし、じゃあ1回深呼吸してから歌うね。
Alright, let's take a deep breath before I sing.
では、私の初めてのオリジナル曲、
Now, my very first original song...
あ、その前に水飲んでいい？
Ah, can I drink some water before that?
では、行きたいと思います。聞いてください。もぐもぐYAMMY！
Well then, I'd like to begin. Please listen. 'Mogumogu YAMMY!'
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も
Even the hardest thing in all the world...
マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる?
will it taste good if you put mayonnaise on it?
君が泣いてもお腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, you'll still get hungry.
消化できなかった「ごめんごめん。」
Couldn't digest it, sorry, sorry.
酸いも甘いも 勝手に食べて
Sour or sweet, I'll eat whatever I want.
ご迷惑おかけしています
Sorry to trouble you!
パクチーな綻 変な味のジュース
A cilantro branch and weird-flavored juice...
心を無にして飲みこみます
I'll gulp it down with an empty heart.
ああ 混沌 情報過多のレストランで
Ah, at a chaotic, info-overload restaurant,
なんだこれ!
What is this?!
おい出してくれ!
Hey, get me out of here!
今日はなんて日だ!
What kind of day is today?
あー
Ah...
やばくない?ちょっと
Isn't this kind of crazy?
もう1回歌わせてくれよ!
Let me sing it one more time!
Let me sing it again!
おいちょっとみんな聞いたか今?
Hey, did everyone listen just now?
今みんなには聞こえない声で
Everyone told me things like,
トークで繋いでくださいとかいう
"Connect with us through your talk,"
むちゃぶりされたぞみんな!
You're all making fun of me, seriously!
僕じゃなきゃこれは怒ってますよ!
If it's not me, I'd be mad about this!
トークで繋いでくださいって言われた。
They told me to "connect with them through talk."
僕フリートーク苦手でさ、
I'm bad at free talk, you know?
いつも雑談する前に事前にみんなから雑談の話題募ってる
I always try to gather chat topics beforehand...
ぐらいななのにね。なんて日だよ本当に!
What kind of day is this, seriously?!
本当に本当に ちょっとちょっとちょっとちょっと!
Really, really, really... wait, wait, wait!
なんだよ!僕が何したって言うんだよ!
Why is this happening? What did I even do?!
ね、もう1回聞けるからって言う意味では確かに行いいいかもくんないね。
Well, I guess you could say "I get to listen to it again."
確かに。
That's true.
ねえ、今日やばいよね!
Right? Today is crazy, right?
画質も最長だったし
The resolution was super high,
あのころさんの回線も謎にやばかったし
And Koro-san's cable was weirdly crazy...
まさかの最後の最後でこんなことになってしまうっていうね!
And then, right at the very, very end, this happens!
これじゃ僕が先に歌う前にプレミア公開されちゃうよ!
If this happens, my premiere gets leaked before I even sing!
僕が先か プレミア公開が先か みたいなとこちょっとあるよね。
It's like, did I go first, or did the premiere go first?
やばい!
This is bad!
自分の動画に負けるの僕?!
Losing to my own video—me?!
ちなみにね22時半から あの
By the way, it premieres at 9:30 PM,
公開されるのでね そちらも そちらも見ていただければなと思います。
so I hope you'll check that out too!
はい。
Yes.
でもやばい、僕より先にそっちがね公開されてしまう可能性がちょっと出てきていますね。
But oh no, what if that gets released before mine?
どっちが先か? プレミア公開が先か Okayuが先か
Which one's first? Premiere or Okayu?
負けたくないよ!負けたくないよ!
I don't wanna lose! I don't wanna lose!
あと15分あと15分。
Only 15 minutes left, only 15 minutes!
助けて!
Help me!
助けてよお!
Help meee!
でもね、ここで誰も助けられないのが現実なんだよな…おかゆ。
But you know, nobody being able to help me is just reality, huh... Okayu.
いやこれ負けるかもしれないな。
Yeah, I might actually lose!
負けるかもしれないんだけど。
I might actually lose, you know.
たくさん人が見てくれてるみたいですみんなありがとう!
Lots of people are watching! Thank you, everyone!
でも今僕は、私はあの壁の中に閉じ込められてます。
But right now, I'm locked inside a wall.
壁の中に閉じ込められてるよ!出してよ!
Locked inside a wall! Let me out!
お腹も空いてきたし、どうしよう。
I'm getting hungry too, what should I do?
あ、今誰か なんかすぱだが付いた、ホロライブのメンバーがすーって取っていた。
Oh, someone just took a snapshot! A Hololive member just zipped by!
誰だった?誰だった今の人?
Who was that? Who was that just now?
誰だった今の人?今誰だった?
Who was that just now? Who was it?
誰だった今の人?みおちゃ?みおちゃ?
Who was that just now? Mio-cha? Mio-cha?
みおちゃあ!
Mio-chaaaaa!
みおちゃはいないんだ、今日は。みおちゃあ!
Mio-cha isn't here today. Mio-chaaaaa!
こんなさ、こんなお預けってばないよね。みんなも辛いよね!
I mean, you can't just leave me waiting like this! Everyone's suffering too!
みんなも辛いよね!えっって。
Everyone's suffering too, right? Seriously?!
マジ?ここで?!
Seriously, right here?!
ねえ、そんな感じですよね。いや私も歌いたいな。
Yeah, it's like that, isn't it? I wanna sing too!
あ!あっ、おかゆ先パイ!聞こえる?聞こえる!
Ah! Okayu-senpai, can you hear us? Can you hear us?!
おかゆ先パイ!アキ・ローゼンタールです。来たよ!待ってた?
Okayu-senpai! It's Aki Rosenthal! We came for you!
おかゆ先パイ!
Okayu-senpai!
あなた、僕今壁に閉じ込められてる。
Kanata, I'm locked inside a wall right now!
おかゆ先輩が見えねえよ！この…この蓋されてたねか…
Okayu-senpai, I can't see you! Being covered up like this...
かなた！この前さ、
Kanata, the other day,
この前一緒にさ、
the other day when we were together,
あの、進撃の巨人でもこういう展開あったよね？
you know, Attack on Titan had a plot like this, right?
壁の中にずっと閉じ込め…巨人じゃないですよおかゆ先輩は！
Trapped inside the wall the whole time—you're not a Titan, Okayu-senpai!
かなた、ずっと見てますよおかゆ先輩！
Kanata, I've been watching you the whole time, Okayu-senpai!
じゃあオリジナル曲もう一回、で、歌ってください！
Then please sing your original song one more time!
ねえ、歌いたいよ！歌いましょうね！
Hey, I want to sing! Let's sing!
えーん、ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ、ちゅ…
(Singing noises) Ee-n, chu, chu, chu, chu...
なんかかなた今日声かわいくない？めっちゃ。
Somehow your voice sounds so cute today, Kanata!
えっ？いや僕思ってたんだけどおかゆ先輩も今日めっちゃ声かわいくないですか？
Eh? Well, I thought Okayu-senpai's voice sounded super cute today too!
えっ？たぶんみんな思ってたと思うわ。
Eh? I bet everyone thought so.
なんか今日初手からさ、あれおかゆ先輩なんか、いつもかわいいけど…えっ？今日もっとかわいい？みたいな。
Somehow right from the start, like, Okayu-senpai is always cute, but... Eh? Even cuter today? Like that.
もうね、あれかもしれない。焦りすぎて声がちょっとうわずっちゃってんのかもしれない。
Maybe it's because I was rushing and my voice got a bit squeaky.
かわいいよ、もう！本当に誕生日おめでとうございます！
You're so cute! Happy birthday for real!
ありがとう！まだかな、まだかなこの壁は…ちょっといっぱいフォロワー呼んできちゃおうかな、僕。
Thank you! I wonder if this wall is still... Maybe I should call in a bunch of followers.
でもかなたちゃんなんか今ね、朗報が入った。
But Kanata-chan, some good news just came in.
お、何々？
Oh, what is it?
僕はついに壁から出られるらしい。
It seems I can finally get out of the wall.
おかえりなさい！それでは殺されましたと、観客に紛れるから！それじゃあかなた、バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Welcome back! Then since you were killed, I'll mingle with the audience! See ya, Kanata, bye-bye! Bye-bye!
天使だなマジで、かなたーん。かなたんのおかげでどうにか行けそうらしいです！
She's a true angel, Kanatan. Thanks to Kanatan, it seems I'll somehow make it!
はあ、よかった！
Haah, I'm so glad!
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる？
Even the arduous struggles of the universe... become mostly delicious with mayonnaise?
君が泣いてもお腹は空くよ 消化できなかった「ごめんごめん。」
Even if you cry, you'll still get hungry—indigestible "Sorries..."
酸いも甘いも勝手に食べて ご迷惑おかけしています
Eating the sour and sweet on my own, causing you trouble.
パクチーな綻 変な味のジュース 心を無にして飲みこみます
Cilantro tears, weird-tasting juice, swallowing it with a blank mind.
ああ 混沌 情報過多のレストランで 嘘っぱちのメニューにお茶こぼして
Ah, in a chaotic, information-overloaded restaurant, spilling tea on a bogus menu,
君と もぐもぐ もぐもぐ 銃撃戦の真ん中で もぐもぐ (うぎゃ～)
munching along with you in the middle of a firefight, mnom mnom (Ugh~)
魅惑魅魎 ハラペコの群れ 満腹になる未来を願っているよ
Bewitching phantoms, a starving horde, wishing for a future where we're full.
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ 世界が終わる前に
Munching away before the world ends,
もぐもぐやみい マジ神 やむやみ ありのまんま
mnom-mnom-yummy, truly divine, aching and yearning just as we are.
もぐもぐやみい Magic Coming この世を味わうんだ うまうま
Mnom-mnom-yummy, Magic Coming, savoring this world, yummy-yummy.
理論武装のミルフィーユサンド (サンド)
The heavily armed mille-feuille sandwich (sandwich)
匿名希望のオーロラソース (ソース)
The anonymous aurora sauce (sauce)
大雑把な味付け 多めにみてよ 美味しくなったら「おｋ。おｋ。」
Overlooking the rough seasoning, once it's delicious, "Ok, ok."
良いモン悪いモン いっぱい食べて 汚れた口元拭います
Eating lots of good and bad things, wiping our soiled mouths.
おにぎり ピザ ケーキ 豪華なフルコース 罠を疑い気をつけます
Rice balls, pizza, cake, a grand full course—watching out for traps.
ああ 妄想流言飛語のバイキングで 毒入りと絶品料理より分けて
Ah, in a buffet of delusions and rumors, sorting out the poisoned and exquisite dishes,
君と もぐもぐ もぐもぐ デスゲームの教室で もぐもぐ (うぎゃ～)
munching with you in a death game classroom, mnom mnom (Ugh~)
魅惑魅魎 ハラペコの群れ 仲の良い君と生き残れたらいいな
Bewitching phantoms, a starving horde, hoping to survive with my dear friend.
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ 数年後もこの場所で
Munching away in this very spot years from now,
もぐもぐやみい マジ神 今夜の晩ごはんは
mnom-mnom-yummy, truly divine, tonight's dinner is...
もぐもぐやみい Magic Coming 次はお前の番だ
Mnom-mnom-yummy, Magic Coming, next is your turn!
もぐもぐやみい マジ神 やむやみ ありのまんま
Mnom-mnom-yummy, truly divine...
もぐもぐやみい　マジ神　やむやむありのまんま
Mogu Mogu Yummy! Truly divine, yam-yam just as you are
もぐもぐやみい　Magic Coming　この世を味わうんだ　うまうま
Mogu Mogu Yummy! Magic Coming, savoring this world, yum-yum
もぐもぐもぐもぐ　もぐもぐもぐもぐ
Mogu-mogu-mogu-mogu, mogu-mogu-mogu-mogu
もぐもぐもぐもぐ　もぐもぐやみい
Mogu-mogu-mogu-mogu, mogu-mogu yummy!
もぐもぐもぐもぐ　もぐもぐもぐもぐ
Mogu-mogu-mogu-mogu, mogu-mogu-mogu-mogu
もぐもぐもぐもぐ　もぐもぐやみい　やみい
Mogu-mogu-mogu-mogu, mogu-mogu yummy, yummy!
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
20時半に、またお会いしましょう！ありがとう！
Let's meet again at 8:30 PM! Thank you!